A web developer living in Halifax, Nova Scotia with over a decade of professional and personal experience in front-end and backend development. A dedicated worker and team player capable of scoping out, planning, and developing advanced, attractive, user-friendly web solutions using modern web

Highlights

- PHP, Laravel, Joomla!, WordPress
- JavaScript/ECMAScript, TypeScript, jQuery, Vue, React, Angular, Node, Webpack, Gulp
- HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Less
- Bootstrap, Tailwind, UIKit
- MySQL, Redis (NoSQL)

- GIT (GitHub, GitLab, Bitbucket)
- Adobe Suite, Affinity Suite, Pixelmator

Web/graphic/print design, Photography

Work Experience

Consulting Full-Stack Web Developer

4/2019 - Present

Code+Mortar, through David Aplin Group

Halifax, Nova Scotia

PHP, Laravel, ECMAScript, TypeScript, Vue, Angular, GraphQL, Ionic Framework, Remote Contract

- Developed additions to a multifaceted project using a combination of Laravel coupled with Vue and GraphQL, and a mobile app built using Ionic Framework and Angular with ECMAScript 2015
- Met with client throughout to discuss project deliverables and gain knowledge through mentoring by client's developers
- Took initiative when requiring or waiting on additional information from the client
- Displayed ability to quickly adapt to new working environments and situations

Full-Stack Web Developer

7/2014 - 8/2018

Electric Playground

Bedford, Nova Scotia

PHP, Joomla!, WordPress, Laravel, ECMAScript, CMS Management

- Displayed initiative in learning and suggesting new solutions and frameworks for client projects
- Engaged with clients along with CEO and lead developer to learn project scope and present project updates
- Quickly built out client websites using a combination of Joomla! CMS and pre-existing base templates using custom CSS and LESS, and customized modules to suit project requirements
- Efficiently maintained content of and upgraded client websites, including article management, individual page content updates, and rebuilding legacy themes for modern CMS versions
- Planned and developed Laravel-based web applications including database design, custom Sass and JavaScript/ECMAScript, and determined the scope of application features
- Collaborated with Creative Director to ensure a high standard of responsive web design across all web projects

Freelance Web Developer

2012 - 2014

Bluenose Creative

Sydney, Nova Scotia

PHP, JavaScript, SilverStripe, Web Design

- Engaged with clients through complete service delivery, finalized projects and handover
- Supported clients through updating and maintaining websites when requested

Additional Work Experience

Web Coordinator (VOLUNTEER)

2009 - Present

Maritimes Y's Men

Halifax, Nova Scotia

PHP, Laravel, Website Management

- Supported the regional website and maintained rapport with regional members including club presidents and regional team
- Completed a total overhaul of the site in November 2017 including enhanced functionality (https://maritimesysmen.com/)

Education

Graphic Design

NSCC – Marconi Campus 2011 - 2013 Sydney, NS Applied Communication Arts & Technologies

NSCC - Marconi Campus

NSCC - Marconi Campus 2010 - 2011

Sydney, NS with Honours

Information Technology & Web Development

NSCC - Truro Campus

2007 - 2010

Truro. NS